Guide to the Richard E. Snow Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2000-150
  - Professional Papers, 1965-1997; Subseries 2
    - Open Office Landscaping Corresp. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Title VII 3805--61--897 Factor Analysis of Film Learning Administration and Budget (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Individual Differences and Instructional Film Repetitions, Snow, Seibert, Heckman (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - [Unlabeled folder] (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - [Unlabeled folder] (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Pygmalion Reviews (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Booklet: Case Study in Statistical Inference: Reconsideration of the Rosenthal--Jacobson Data on Teacher Expectancy (Box 15)
    - Cronbach Comments on Rosenthal (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Rebuttal--Elashoff and Snow (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence (requests) (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Charles A. Jones (pub.) (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Gage preface (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Pygmalion Review Drafts (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Pygmalion Data (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Pygmalion Requests, Copies to be sent out in Jan. 1970 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - "Pygmalion" Requests (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Pygmalion Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Vita 12/1/80 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - CPSE (Psychological Studies in Education) --Cognitive Psychology (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - School of Education. Task Force on Teacher Education (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - CPSE 1986-87 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - CPSE recruitment (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Academic Senate -- Alternate (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - CPSE current (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - CPSE long range (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - CPSE program procedures (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - [Unlabeled – assorted items] (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - CPSE retreat (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Studies – current (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Ed. Psych. Core (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - SUSE reorganization (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Prospective faculty (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - [Unlabeled] (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - L.J. Cronbach billet replacement (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Psych. Studies Qual. kit (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - General Media Research Questions (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Research Conference on Learning and the Educ. Process, Stanford University -- computer simulation (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Research Conference on Learning and the Educ. Process, Stanford University, 1965 -- I (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Research Conference on Learning and the Educ. Process, Stanford University, 1965 -- II (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Summer conference participants (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - NUFFIC Summer Institute, NSF Travel Support (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - PAGSIP Alumni directory, Dept. of Political Sciences, Purdue University, March 1972 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Preliminary notes (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Preliminary examinations (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Industrial Engineering (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Human Engineering, Psych 576 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Psychology 605 Tests and Measurement (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Psychology 574 Industrial Training (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Psychology 615 Psychophysical Methods and Psychological Scaling (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Industrial Psychology (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Consumer Psychology (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Psych 675 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Human Relations Psych 673 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Labor Law I and II (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Physiological Psychology -- notes (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Statistics -- miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Notes on factor analysis -- Brogden (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Stat 580 Machine Methods -- IBM system (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - FORTRAN (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Teaching Machines -- Programmed Instruction (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Item analysis research (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Project Challenge (conference info) (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Title VII Information Proposals (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - R. Heckman – graduate work (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Instruction Studies Discussion Group (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Campus Audio Visual (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Sources of Support for Research (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - FAU and New College and other Florida Institutions (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Notecards from Purdue (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Notecards from Purdue (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - SUSE, Atkin, etc. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Dean's Advisory Committee, 1981-82 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Journal reviewing (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Farr meeting -- AERA (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Jack Alpert (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Journal of Educational Psychology, misc. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Reviews of journal mss. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Willingham GRE study (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - OERI Technology Center (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - U.S. National Committee International Union of Psych. Sci. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Nijhoff, Martinus (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - AFT Conference July 30-Aug. 2, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - NPRDC CAT activity constructs (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - [binder] Committee on Educational Policy (SUSE), 1985-86 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - [binder] Committee on Educational Policy (SUSE), sub-committee files, 1985-86 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - CEP (Committee on Educational Policy) (Box 18, Folder 1819)
    - Ed Policy Committee, 1987-88 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - SUSE faculty matters (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - CEP faculty survey (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - CEP (Committee on Educational Policy) (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Academic Senate (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - CEP 1986-87 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Box labeled: Miscellaneous Correspondence 1987-1992 [mostly unfoldered] (Box 19)
    - Box labeled: Miscellaneous Correspondence 1993-1997 [mostly unfoldered] (Box 20)
  - Restricted Files, Subseries 3
    - Letters of Recommendation (Box 21)
    - Letters of Recommendation (Box 21)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2003-049
  - Snow – c.v. 1992-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Obituary 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-June 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Correspondence, June-Dec. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, 1996-97 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chron file 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - CRESST correspondence, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ETS Award 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - NAE Ad Hoc nominations 1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - PSE Futures 1997 [re educational psychology in SUSE] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Human Abilities (Psych 133/ED255) bibliography 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Human Abilities (Psych 133/Ed255) course reader 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Master list of references (Box 2-6, Folder 3)
  - Diaz, Rafael Miguel, "Latino Gay Men and the Psycho-Cultural Barriers to Aids Prevention" (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hakuta, K., "Language Shift in a Mexican-American Community" (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hamilton, Linda – papers, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hativa, Nira – correspondence and research proposals (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Melton, Walter C. & Snow, "A First Order Dynamic Model for the Effect of Environment on Mental Development," with related correspondence, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Melton, Walter C. & Snow, "Toward a Dynamic Model of Mental Development" with related correspondence 1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Winsler, Adam, "The social Origins of Self-Regulatory Private Speech in Attention Deficit-Hyperactive and Normal Children," dissertation proposal 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Snow, "Abilities as Aptitudes and Achievements in Learning Situations," 1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Snow, "Aptitude Development in Education" – correspondence and figures for, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Snow, "Aptitude-Treatment Interaction as a Framework for research on Individual Differences in Psychotherapy," 1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes and Symbol Systems in Adaptive Classroom Teaching" (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Snow, "Assessment of Cognitive and Conative Constructs for Educational Research: A Catalogue," draft, Oct. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Snow and Michele Ennis, "Correlates of High Mathematical Ability in a National Sample of Eighth Graders, " 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Snow, "An Unbiased History of EARLI from One American's Point of View," with related correspondence, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Snow, "Validity of IQ as a Measure of Cognitive Ability" – miscellaneous notes only (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Snow, assorted chapters from published works (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Snow, reprints 1981, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Snow, reprints 1986-87 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 1, 1997 – diskette and notebook label (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 1, 1997 – chapter 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 1, 1997 – chapter 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 1, 1997 – chapter 3-4 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 1, 1997 – chapter 5-8 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 1, 1997 – miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 2, 1997 – diskettes, miscellaneous, and notebook label (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 2, 1997 – preface, chapter 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 2, 1997 – chapter 2-3 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 2, 1997 – chapter 4-5 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 2, 1997 – chapter 6-7 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 2, 1997 – chapter 8 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 2, 1997 – chapter 9 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Snow, "Aptitudes" version 2, 1997 – miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Computer diskettes and indexes for selected diskettes (Box 5)